A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Alison R. Bernstein FA573
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Executive Officer Subject Files, 1975-2010; 22.38 Cubic Feet 58 containers
  - Difficult Dialogues - Summary Report of the Conference, "Maintaining a Free and Open Campus Environment," Hosted by the Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program, Karen Kennerly, 2004 April 30 (Box 78, Folder 670)
  - Philanthropy in Europe: Opportunities and Challenges, A Primer for the Ford Foundation, Mihaela Serban, 2006 June (Box 78, Folder 671)
  - Exploring Aspects of Grantmaking in Europe: A Ford Foundation Workshop Hosted by the Stephan Batory Foundation, Warsaw, Mia Serban, 2006 June 14-15 (Box 78, Folder 672)
  - Faculty Accomodation Committee, 2001-2004 (Box 78, Folder 673)
  - Meeting with Richard L. McCormick, Rutgers President, Affirmative Action, and General Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 78, Folder 674)
  - College Board of Study - Improving the Quality of Education for American Indians, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 675)
  - Ford Foundation Office of Communications Survey and Materials Audit, 2006 (Box 78, Folder 676)
  - Convening of Women Religious Activists, 2003 May 13-14 (Box 78, Folder 677)
  - Council on Foundations 55th Annual Conference, 2004 (Box 78, Folder 678)
  - Democratizing the Media, Prepared for the Aspen Institute/Ford Foundation International Roundtable on Journalism and Freedom of Expression, Ann C. Hudock, 2003 November 12-14 (Box 78, Folder 679)
  - CIG: Cultural Institutions Group, Karen Brooks Hopkins Correspondence and Briefing Book, 2001-2004 (Box 79, Folder 680)
  - Photocopies of Ford Foundation Building Information Pamphlet, undated (Box 79, Folder 681)
  - Robert Burnet, Program Officer Memo, Media, Arts and Culture in Eastern Africa, 2003 November (Box 79, Folder 682)
  - Laura Bush, The White House Conference on Global Literacy, New York Public Library, 2006 September 18 (Box 79, Folder 683)
  - Sexuality and Reproductive Health Learning Group Meeting in Cairo Planning, 2003 September (Box 79, Folder 684)
  - Carnegie Corporation - Teachers for a New Era, 2003-2005 (Box 79, Folder 685)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching (CFAT) Studies, 2003 (Box 79, Folder 686)
  - Annual Conference for Corporate and Foundation Relations, CASE (Council for the Advancement and Support of Education) - Keynote Speech, 2003 (Box 79, Folder 687)
  - Proposed Center for the Study of Democratic Civil Society: A National Resource Center at The Pennsylvania State University, 2006 (Box 79, Folder 688)
  - The Character Studies Education Project, 2005 (Box 79, Folder 689)
  - Jack Kent Cooke Foundation, Community College Transfer Initiative Advisory Board Foundation, 2005 October 25 (Box 79, Folder 690)
  - Mary Frances Berry's Concept Paper: Forum Series on Social Justice - United States Commission on Human Rights, 2005 March (Box 79, Folder 691)
  - BAM (Brooklyn Academy of Music) Local Development Corporation, 2003 (Box 79, Folder 692)
  - Barnard College Proposal - Literature of the Middle Passage, Ghana Trip, 2004 (Box 79, Folder 693)
  - Biennial Budget Papers 2004-2005, 2003 (Box 79, Folder 694)
  - US-Vietnam Dialogue on Agent Orange/Dioxin, Meeting III, 2008 January 29-February 1 (Box 79, Folder 695)
  - Integrating the Arts and Education Reform: An EMAC Exploration, Draft by Cyrus Driver, 2001 December (Box 79, Folder 696)
  - ArtSource Wellspring Presentation and General Ford Art Funding Information, 2002 (Box 79, Folder 697)
  - Asian University for Women in Bangladesh, Rhode Island School of Design and Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2004 (Box 79, Folder 698)
  - Ford Foundation African Higher Education Initiative (AHEI) Partnership for Higher Education in Africa (PHEA) Annual Meeting, 2008 November 15-16 (Box 80, Folder 699)
  - Affirmative Action Initiative, 2004-2006 (Box 80, Folder 700)
  - African Studies at the Millennium: A Review of Ford Foundation African Studies Grantees, 1995-1997, Martha Gephart, Angelique Haugerud, Michael Watts (Box 80, Folder 701)
  - Ford Foundation Meeting of the Board of Trustees, 2008 September 25 (Box 80, Folder 702)
  - National Black Arts Festival Proposal, 2007 December (Box 80, Folder 703)
  - Joyce Theater - Performing Arts Center at the World Trade Center Site Proposal, 2007 (Box 80, Folder 704)
  - Receipts of Ford Foundation Book Donations from Libraries at Colleges and Universities - Inclusive Scholarship: Developing Black Studies in the United States, 2008 (Box 80, Folder 705)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Trustee Visit to Vietnam Briefing Book, 2004 May 1-8 (Box 80, Folder 706)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Infographic - Board Meeting, 2008 September (Box 80, Folder 707)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Trustee Committee Meeting, 2008 January 30 (Box 80, Folder 708)
  - Detroit: Cultural Alliance of Southeastern Michigan, 2008 (Box 80, Folder 709)
  - Ford Fellows' Conference, Washington D.C., 2008 September 19-20 (Box 80, Folder 710)
  - College Affordability: The Wolf in Sheep's Clothing, Tony Carnevale, Inside Higher Ed, 2009 (Box 81, Folder 711)
  - HBCU Support and Related Organization Comparative Analysis, United Negro College Fund, Michael Lomax, 2007 (Box 81, Folder 712)
  - Edits to China, Mexico, Namibia, and South Africa Pathways Web Pages, Sharon Lewis, 2008 (Box 81, Folder 713)
  - Vietnam Ministry of Health Visit to Ford Foundation, 2006 July 21 (Box 81, Folder 714)
  - Ed Lauman - Discussion on New Research on Women's Sexuality Findings in 29 Countries, 2005 (Box 81, Folder 715)
  - Albie Sachs - Proposal for a Grant From the Ford Foundation New York to the Constitutional Court Trust: Book on Artworks of the Constitutional Court, 2008 (Box 81, Folder 716)
  - Abdullah Ahmed An-Na'im, Resident Scholar at the Ford Foundation Correspondence, 2007 (Box 81, Folder 717)
  - United Negro College Fund (UNCF)/Fisk University Conference Call, 2008 February 29 (Box 81, Folder 718)
  - Difficult Dialogues Initiative Letters, 2008 March (Box 81, Folder 719)
  - Understanding and Combating Anti-Semitism in Europe - Draft Summary Report, Brussels, Belgium, Karen Kennerly, 2004 May 12 (Box 81, Folder 720)
  - Ford Foundation Wordwide Meeting - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program, Beijing, 2006 (Box 81, Folder 721)
  - Correspondence Regarding Ford Foundation Profile in New York Times and Wall Street Journal about CCNY's Rangel Center, 2007-2008 (Box 81, Folder 722)
  - Southern Education Foundation, Lynn Huntley Correspondence, 2010 (Box 81, Folder 723)
  - Vassar Quarterly - Alison Bernstein Article, 1998 (Box 81, Folder 724)
  - Origins, Journeys and Returns, Social Justice in International Higher Education, Toby Alice Volkman with Joan Dassin and Mary Zurbuchen, 2009 (Box 81, Folder 725)
  - Ford Foundation Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program, Trustee Committee Visit to Vietnam, Background Materials, 2004 May 1-8 (Box 82, Folder 726)
  - Correspondence from Reverend Rick Ryscavage, Fairfield University - Strangers as Neighbors: Religious Language and the Response to Immigrants in the U.S., 2008-2009 (Box 82, Folder 727)
  - Is Philanthropy Abandoning Higher Education?, Alison Bernstein, 2003 (Box 82, Folder 728)